hey everybody welcome to this a2
english listening practice video you can
use this video to practice your
listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start
remember to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram you ready so today
i'm gonna talk about dentist
appointments
personally i don't like this topic at
all
because i don't like going to the
dentist but it's a pretty
important topic so why don't we talk
about it
in the u.s going to the dentist is a
normal part of people's lives
many people go to the dentist once twice
or three times a year for routine
checkups
during a normal checkup the dentist
cleans your teeth
and checks to see if you have any major
problems
i hate the way that dentists clean teeth
because for me
it feels really uncomfortable first they
use a tool
to scrape off all the plaque plaque is
the stuff that forms on your teeth
from eating things such as sugar it's
not good to have a lot of plaque
so the dentist removes it during your
checkup
i think it's uncomfortable when they do
this but
i know it's necessary sometimes the
dentist needs to remove
plaque from around your gums your gums
are the pink parts above and below your
teeth
if your gums are unhealthy they can
bleed
when the dentist cleans your mouth when
i was younger
my gums would always bleed during my
dentist appointments
so after the dentist removes your plaque
they usually brush and floss your teeth
then they check for cavities if you
don't take good care of your teeth
it's easy to develop cavities children
often get a lot of cavities
because they eat a lot of sugar and they
don't clean their teeth well
i had three cavities when i was younger
but now i take
better care of my teeth i hope i don't
get any more cavities in the future
nowadays i usually brush my teeth twice
a day
and i floss twice a day too in the u.s
it's normal for people to brush their
teeth in the morning
and at night but many people don't floss
i rarely flossed when i was younger and
it was the same for most of my friends
but now it feels really weird if i don't
floss
because i've developed the habit how
about you
how often do you brush and floss your
teeth
so another reason why people go to the
dentist or orthodontist
is for braces i got braces when
i was 21 and i had them until i was 23.
i really hated having braces they looked
horrible
and they made it really hard to clean my
teeth
i remember how much i hated flossing
when i had braces
i'm glad i don't have them anymore
lastly
let's talk about the price of going to
the dentist or orthodontist
in the u.s many people have dental
insurance which covers most of the cost
but if you don't have insurance it can
be
really expensive in other countries it's
much cheaper
for example in mexico it's cheap and
easy to see a dentist or get braces
you probably don't need insurance
because the price
usually isn't that high but of course
some procedures are more expensive than
others
and it could be a lot of money if you
need a lot of work done
on your mouth but overall dental care
is much more expensive in the u.s
alright that's all for today
leave a comment and tell me if you go to
the dentist regularly
and remember to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell
and follow us on instagram for more
english tips and lessons
i'll see you next time
[Music]
[Applause]
you